Sina Mohseni

Langford Center, B208, 3137 TAMU, College Station, Texas 77840

□ (+1) 541-745-8849 | ■ sina.mohseni@tamu.edu | 🏶 people.tamu.edu/sina.mohseni/ | 🗖 sinamohseni | 🛅 sina-mohsen

Objective _

Talented computer science researcher with 8+ years of experience in research, patents, publications, and 4+ years of experience in machine learning, data visualization, and crowdsourcing design. Passionate to use my technical and leadership skills to run innovative projects as a computer science research scientist. Seeking a research-oriented full-time position for Fall 2020.

Professional Experience _____

Deep Learning Safety Research Intern at Nvidia

Santa Clara, California

Apr. 2019 - Aug. 2019

"Out-of-distribution Error Detection for DNN Algorithms", Nvidia Drive.

- Proposed a new out-of-distribution error detection method based on self-supervised training (PyTorch)
 (AAAI accepted paper, pending patent)
- Studied relation between classic engineering safety methods and deep learning safety-related techniques. (submitted to SafeAl 2020 workshop)
- Designed a transfer learning approach for model failure prediction in autonomous vehicle applications. (PilotNet, TensorFlow)

Research Intern at Bosch Research and Technology Center

Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania

"INTEGRATING CROWD AND AI FOR LIDAR DATA ANNOTATION IN SELF-DRIVING CARS APPLICATION", CROWD-AI PROJECT.

May. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Implemented a 3D LiDAR data annotation tool for crowdworkers to create training data for self-driving car applications. (Three.js)
- · Designed and implemented micro task and work flows for LiDAR data annotation in Amazon Mechanical Turk. (MongoDB, Flask)

Graduate Research Assistant at Texas A&M University

College Station, Texas

"EXPLAINABLE ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE", DARPA XAI GRANT

Aug. 2017 - Present

- · Crowdsourced evaluation of a user-centered interpretable fakenews detection system. (ongoing)
- Designed a user centered interpretable machine learning interface for our fake news detection system. (D3.js, Flask)
- Proposed human judgment evaluation benchmark for explanations from interpretable machine learning. (D3.js, OpenCV)

"Analytic Provenance Visualization and Segmentation", NSF Research Grant.

Sept. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Designed a user interaction clustering and visualization method for provenance retrieval. (D3.js)
- Designed a provenance segmentation method to segment user work by user interaction processing. (D3.js, Scikit-learn, Gensim)

Graduate Research Assistant at Oregon State University

Corvallis, Oregon

"Shrinkage Factor CAD Automation Toolbox", Center for e-Design Grant

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2016

 Implemented a design automation toolbox to apply investment casting shrinkage factors at Design Engineering Lab with Prof. Matt Campbell. (Parasolid kernel, Solidworks)

Graduate Research Assistant at Babol Noshirvani University

Babol, Iran

"Competition Over Resource: A new Metaheuristic Optimization Algorithm", Digital Signal Processing Lab

Jan. 2014 - Aug. 2015

• Designed a new meta-heuristic optimization algorithm based on competitive behavior of animal groups and later used in array antenna design, resulting in five peer-reviewed papers. (Matlab)

"FACIAL EXPRESSION RECOGNITION", DIGITAL SIGNAL PROCESSING LAB

Sept. 2013 - Dec. 2014

• Developed a facial expression recognition algorithm to improve recognition accuracy by leveraging anatomical structure of human face. (Matlab)

Technical Skills_

Languages: Python, C++, C#, MATLAB, JavaScript.

Machine Learning: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Scikit-learn, OpenCV, LIME, Gensim, SpaCy, XGBoost.

Visualization and UI: D3.js, Three.js, Matplotlib.

Crowdsourcing: Workflow and Micro Task Design, User Behavior Analysis, Micro-payment Models, Task Expert-pool.

UX and HCI:

User Centered Design, Usability Test, Controlled Experiment Design, Empirical Methods and

Statistical Analysis, Interaction Logs Analysis.

DECEMBER 2, 2019 SINA MOHSENI · RÉSUMÉ

Education

Texas A&M University

College Station, Texas

COMPUTER SCIENCE PH.D. CANDIDATE

Sept. 2016 - PRESENT

• Proposal Topic: Toward a design and evaluation framework for explainable machine learning systems.

Babol Noshirvani University (NUT)

Babol, Iran

M.Sc. in Electronic Engineering

Sept. 2012 - Dec 2014

• Thesis: Facial Expression Recognition Based on Anatomy of Face

University of Isfahan

Isfahan, Iran

B.Sc. in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

Sept. 2007 - Dec 2011

Patents

Insulator Leakage Current Monitoring and Alarm System in Power Transmission Systems

Iran

NATIONAL PATENT NO.: IRP/021579

Summer 2015

Blood Pressure Monitor Calibrating Device and Corresponding Method

Euro-PCT

INTERNATIONAL PATENT No.: PCT/EP2012/070412

Spring 2010

Publications

Selected Peer-Reviewed Publications

- [1] **Mohseni, Sina**, Pitale, M., Yadawa, J., & Wang, Z.. "Self-Supervised Learning for Generalizable Out-of-Distribution Detection.". AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, AAAI, 2020 [accepted].
- [2] **Mohseni, Sina**. "Toward Design and Evaluation Framework for Interpretable Machine Learning Systems." Proceedings of the 2019 AAAI/ACM Conference on AI, Ethics, and Society. ACM, 2019.
- [3] **Mohseni, Sina**, Zarei, N., and Ramazani, S.. "Facial expression recognition using anatomy based facial graph." Systems, Man and Cybernetics (SMC), 2014 IEEE International Conference on. IEEE, 2014.

Selected Preprint

- [4] **Mohseni, S.**, Ragan, E., Hu, Xia. Open Issues in Combating Fake News: Interpretability as an Opportunity. arXiv preprint arXiv:1904.03016v1, 2019.
- [5] Mohseni, S., Zarei, N., Ragan, E.. A Survey of Evaluation Methods and Measures for Interpretable Machine Learning. arXiv preprint arXiv:1811.11839, 2018.

Honors & Awards

Research Grant (PI), Golestan Province Power Distribution Co.

Gorgan, Iran

"INSULATOR LEAKAGE CURRENT MONITORING SYSTEM IN POWER TRANSMISSION SYSTEMS"

Oct. 2014 - Aug. 2015

- Developed a creepage current meter device which measures micro ampere current from ceramic power transmission insulators.
- Gained more expertise in proposal writing, project management and problem solving.

Research Grant (Co-PI), Isfahan Province Regional Power Distribution Co.

Isfahan, Iran

2

"STUDY ON EFFECTS OF CFL LAMP ON POWER DISTRIBUTION SYSTEM"

Mar. 2011 - Sept. 2011

- · Researched current harmonic effects on power distribution system by performing harmonic analysis in Matlab.
- · Learned proposal writing and project management skills.

Travel Awards

- AIES CONFERENCE TRAVEL AWARD 2019
- GRACE HOPPER CELEBRATION TRAVEL AWARD 2018

Professional Services

Regular Paper Reviewer for ACM CHI, UIST, CSCW, ICWSM, and IEEE VIS conferences since 2017.